なんば　むった
(南波六太)ヘ…ヘックション｡
だいじょうぶ
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)大丈夫？ これをかけて｡
Are you okay?
Use this.
サンキュー ケンジ｡大丈夫だ｡
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)少し 冷えたのかもね｡
Thanks, Kenji.
I'm okay.
It's getting chilly...
Yeah.
This is bad...
《ヤバイなぁ…｡
お腹が すいてきたせいか➡
I'm getting so hungry, that looks like
私には ど～も あれが➡
a churro topped with cotton candy.
ワタアメの付いた
チュロスに見える…》
《あ～～ ダメダメ》
Stop it!
While I was out scavenging, I came across this.
(新田)焚き木に おあつらえ向き
のがあったぜ！➡
If we toss it in, the fire should last all night.
こいつを くべれば
ひとばん
焚き火は一晩もつぜ！
Nice, Nitta!
ナイス！新田君！
(北村)すごい！燃えそう｡
That should burn well!
Churros!
《チュロス！》
A rocket!
ロケットだ！
(南波母)ねえ この
マルスワンって やつ…➡
So about this Mars I...
Can we really trust this thing?
ホントに大丈夫なの この人？
こんなに細くて…｡
It's so skinny.
なんか たよりないわぁ…｡
Doesn't look too reliable.
近くで見りゃ ぶっといから｡
It's not skinny when you're next to it.
ちゃんと まっすぐ飛ぶ？
Does it fly straight?
Yes.
いや…飛ぶよ！
But I've never seen a bottle rocket that flew straight.
だって
母ちゃん…ロケット花火が➡
まっすぐ
飛んだためしがないのよね～｡
(母)あらぬ方向へ飛んでったり➡
It zigzags around,
かと思えば
その場に居座ったり…｡
or it doesn't move at all...
あのな…
ナサ
ＮＡＳＡだぞ ＮＡＳＡ！➡
Come on, we're talking about NASA.
It won't just sit there.
居座らね～よ！
そうよね…ＮＡＳＡだもんね｡
That's right.
It's NASA.
The weather seems to be improving,
(ﾚﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)天気は 回復に
向かっていますが➡
but it's still hard to call.
打ち上げ続行か中止か 現時点での
確率は５対５だということです｡
At the moment, it's a fifty-fifty call.
Fifty-fifty...
《５対５か…》
The person to watch on this mission would be the Samurai Boy, Nanba Hibito.
今回 注目すべきは やはり
サムライボｰイことナンバ･ヒビト｡
日本人初という
にな
大役を担うと同時に➡
He will become the first Japanese person on the moon,
最年少ムーンウォーカーの記録を
こうしん
更新することになります｡
while also setting the mark for the youngest person on the moon.
《あ～ なんだろう…
この気持ちは…》
What is this feeling?
I'm certainly proud of Hibito...
《私はもちろん 日々人のことを
ほこ
誇りに思っている｡➡
I'm as happy for him as I'd be for myself.
うれ
自分のことのように嬉しい｡
そう思える自分がいる｡➡
That's what I believe.
But the other half of me
だが 私の中のもう半分では…》
《いまだにウジウジと
優れた弟に対する➡
is sprouting jealousy germs because I'm envious of my little brother.
じゅうまん
ジェラシー菌が充満してやがる》
(ｼﾞｪﾗｼｰ菌)⦅ウジウジウジ…⦆
It's sad that I can't commit in either direction...
A fifty-fifty split between pride and envy.
しっと
《誇りと嫉妬が５対５だ》
I'm just like...
《これじゃまるで➡
...the weather today.
今日の天気じゃねぇ～か》
I wish the skies would clear up.
《晴れりゃいいのに…》
And I wish
《空も…俺も》
my heart would, too.
SPACE BROTHERS
You've always been in my heart
But you don't say a thing or even smile
We've always been together
We're ignorant, but we believe
All the time I spent with you
Felt like a dream
We connected the stars and drew pictures
To our hearts' content
Let our hearts, shivering in excitement,
Use the sky as a canvas
And merge to form an everlasting image
T minus 30 seconds.
#54 Do I Have Good Luck?
３０秒前｡固体ロケットモーターの
ジンバルテスト中｡
Booster gimbal profile.
(ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)２０秒前｡➡
T minus 20 seconds.
Activate main engine hydrogen burn-off system.
点火システム オン｡➡
水消音システム 作動｡➡
Activate sound suppression water.
T minus 10 seconds.
１０秒前｡➡
ナイン
エイト
９！ ８！➡
9.
8.
セブン
シックス
７！ ６！➡
7.
6.
ファイブ
フォー
５！ ４！➡
5.
4.
3.
スリー
３！２！➡
2.
1.
ワン
１！イグニッション！
Ignition.
ううっ…ううっ～…｡
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)見ろ ムッタ｡➡
Look, Mutta.
リフトオフだ！
We have liftoff.
うわぁ～～…｡
Wow...
まっ まっぶし～！
It's blinding.
スリーツー　ワン
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)３･２･１｡
3.
2.
1.
(アポ)ワン！
Whoa...
《すげえ！なんだ この音！》
Crazy.
That was a huge roar.
Go.
行け…行け…行けえ！
Go!
なんば
ひびと
(南波日々人)うっひょ～！
はな
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)第一段ロケット切り離し！
Disconnecting first stage.
Yeah, he's gone.
あ～あ 行っちまった｡
あっ…けね～｡
That was quick...
着いたか？宇宙｡
Has he made it into space?
はあっ おほっ はっ ははっ｡
I finally made it...
来ちゃった！
(バディ)へへへ…あっけない
もんだろ｡ヒビト｡➡
Doesn't take long, does it, Hibito?
地上から ここまで
たったの８分｡➡
Half a minute from the surface to space.
But it took five years of training for you to get here, Hibito.
飛行士に選ばれてからの道のり｡➡
くんれん
５年も訓練して待ってたのにな
ヒビト｡➡
いっしゅん
来るのは一瞬だもんな｡
The trip just takes an instant...
５年じゃ すまね～な｡
It took a lot longer than five years.
２０年 待ってたよ｡こん時を｡
I've been waiting twenty years for this moment.
He...
《あいつ…本当に宇宙に
行きやがったな》
really made it to space...
⦅ムッちゃんが行かなくても
俺は絶対 宇宙に行くからな…⦆
Even if you don't want to go to space, I'm still going to make it.
⦅君はアレだね 日々人君⦆
Yeah, Hibito...
⦅昔から｢絶対 絶対｣って
軽～く言っちゃうけども➡
You always throw the word "definitely" around.
世の中に絶対なんて
ないんじゃねぇかなあ…⦆
But nothing is definite in this world...
Sure.
⦅そうだな…世の中には
｢絶対｣はないかもな⦆
Nothing is definite in this world.
⦅え…？⦆
⦅でも 大丈夫⦆
Huh?
But it's okay.
⦅俺ん中にあるから⦆
Some things within me are definite.
The rocket road allows no detours.
《ロケットロードは
寄り道をしない｡➡
There's no turning back, either.
後戻りもしない｡➡
ただ一直線に 宇宙へ伸びる道｡➡
It's a straight path up to space.
Just like you, Hibito.
まんま お前みたいだな 日々人》
しょくん
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)それでは諸君…｡
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
Let's go to the moon.
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)月へ行こう｡
It appears that everyone has signed the waiver.
しょうだく
どうやら 全員 承諾して
頂いたようですね｡➡
では
説明しますので 今から言う➡
Before I explain the next part,
we need you to divide into three teams.
はん
Ａ Ｂ Ｃの３班に分かれて下さい｡
３班？
Three teams?
(鶴見)まずはＡ班｡➡
First, we have Team A.
Ｂ班｡➡
Team B.
そして Ｃ班｡
And Team C.
この５人１組の
Ａ Ｂ Ｃの３班は➡
These three five-person teams
バスの中で皆さんに書いて頂いた
もと
こうせい
アンケートを元に構成しました｡➡
were assigned based on the surveys you completed on the bus.
これから Ａ Ｂ Ｃ ３班は➡
Next, Teams A, B, and C will each enter separate sealed environments.
へいさかんきょう
それぞれ 別の閉鎖環境ボックスに
入ってもらいます｡
そこで２週間…
あた
さまざま
かだい
与えられる様々な課題を➡
The five team members will spend the two weeks working together to complete various tasks.
５人で協力し合い
こなしていって下さい｡
(古谷)なんや これ…！
(新田)ひでえな｡
What the hell?
That's pretty ugly.
(古谷)誰や？➡
Who was it?
こんなことしたヤツ！
Who the hell did this?
俺はてっきり 古谷がまた
こわ
踏み壊したと思ったけどな｡
I assumed you accidentally stepped on something again.
《空気悪い…》
Eh?
It's really tense in here...
あ～ 何なんだ？この音…｡
うるせえな おい｡
What's that noise?
Keep it down, man!
(福田)どこで鳴ってるんだ？
Where is it coming from?
あ～ 止まった｡
Oh, it stopped...
＜我々は ビービーうるせえ 謎の
アラーム音に叩き起こされた＞
We were woken up by a loud beeping.
何なんだ？
次から次へと｡
Why are we having so many issues?
＜次々と起こる謎の事件は
ＪＡＸＡからの指令➡
Eventually, I realized we kept having trouble because NASA was issuing orders via green cards.
グリーンカードであることに
私は気づいた＞
《え～!?》
Orders
Shout abruptly, to startle the other members.
You must do this twice daily, until the last day.
Do not respond if the other members
ask about your behavior.
Do not tell anyone about this green card
or the orders you received.
ポウ！
ヒィ!?
なんや いきなり！
What was that?
ウホンッ！
《マイケル･ジャクソン…》
Michael Jackson.
《わかってくれよ みんな…｡
ＪＡＸＡの指示なんだ！》
Please understand, everyone...
I'm following orders from JAXA.
《グリーンカードだからなっ
これは！》
I've been given a green card!
なぁ みんな…｡
Hey...
Guys...
宇宙の話をしよう｡
Let's talk about space.
U-Um, which observatory are you talking about?
あの…天文台って
どこのですって？
え？ああ
シャロンおばちゃんのね｡
Huh?
Oh, this was Aunt Sharon's observatory.
What?!
シャロンって あの
カネコ･シャロン博士？
Do you mean Dr. Kaneko Sharon?
The astronomer?!
天文学者の!?
そ～だよ｡
Yeah.
本当に!?私 本持ってます！
Really?!
I own one of her books!
マジか ジブン!?
うん｡英語も教えてもらったよ｡
Are you serious?
Yeah.
She taught me English.
え～いいな～‼
うらやましい話だな｡
Wow! That's great...
You're making me jealous.
確か シャロンっていう名前の
小惑星があるんだよな｡
Isn't there an asteroid named Sharon?
そうです そうです！
Yeah...
That's right! That's right!
同じ天文学者で旦那さんの
金子進一博士が発見して➡
Her husband, Kaneko Shinichi, also an astronomer, discovered it and named it after his wife!
奥さんの名前をつけたんですよ！
ねっ 南波さん？
Isn't that right, Nanba?
Yeah, that's right.
ああ そうだよ｡
《すっげ～｡みんな
シャロンのこと知ってるんだ》
Wow...
Everyone knows Sharon...
《今まで こんなこと
一度もなかった…》
This hasn't ever happened before.
But they were right here.
《ここにいたんだ》
People who would've been eager to come along.
《誘ったら 喜んで
ついて来てくれそうな連中が》
《ここに…いたんだ…》
They've been here all this time.
どこ行くの？
公園！よくわかんね～けど➡
Where are you going?
The park.
Someone from JAXA asked me to meet him there since he's in the area.
近くまで来たから 出てこれないか
って…ＪＡＸＡの人が｡
《こういうもんなのか!?
合格発表って》
Is this how the announcement is supposed to happen?
JAXA actually sends people to meet us?
《ＪＡＸＡの人が
わざわざ来るのか？》
ほしか
(星加)よう！
Hi.
《あれ この人は確か…》
Huh?
Isn't he...
アンアン ク～ン｡
シー！シー！
Shh... Shh!
モジャ君…いや 南波六太君｡
Afro...
No, Nanba Mutta.
はい｡
Yes.
我々ＪＡＸＡは 君を…｡
We at JAXA
would...
(星加)⦅台本覚えてんのか
あいつら？➡
They've memorized the script?
Those kids are the ones who end up becoming astronauts...
あ～いうのが将来 宇宙飛行士に
なったりすんだよな⦆
君を…宇宙飛行士として
迎えます｡
...would like to welcome you as a new astronaut.
おめでとう！君には運がある｡
Congratulations.
You're one of the lucky ones.
あ ありがとうございます｡
Th-Thank you very much.
遅くなって悪かったね｡
直接 伝えたかったんだ｡
Sorry about being so late.
I wanted to tell you in person.
いえ…ありがとうございます｡
Thank you very much.
(チリン チリン チリン…)
(母)う…うう…｡➡
やったわ あの子…｡
He did it...
うう…よかったわ｡➡
I'm so happy for him.
アポちゃん
ケーキ買って帰りましょ｡
Apo,
let's buy a cake and go home.
(アポ)ワン！
じゃあ 行こうか 六太君｡
え!? 行くって どこに？
Then let's go, Mutta.
Huh?
Wh-Where are we going?
向こうに車を待たせてある｡
There's a car waiting for us.
これから さっそく記者会見だ！
We should head straight to the press conference.
他の合格者も
みんな向かってる頃だ｡
The other new astronauts are waiting.
みんなも…｡
The other new astronauts?
(星加)さあ 急ごう‼
Let's hurry!
(チリン チリン チリン…)
いやいやいやっ ええやんかっ！
Well, well, well.
You all look very sharp.
にお
みんな よう似合てるわぁ！
《うわ… ぽい…》
Yeah...
《なんか…➡
This is it...
ぽくなってきた‼》
Now this is more like it!
(紫)さて みんな！➡
Okay, everyone.
ジャンプスーツを着て
気分が高まってきたところだろう｡
I'm sure you're excited, putting on
your jumpsuits for the first time.
その意気込みのまま 我々は
明日の朝 出発する｡わかってんね｡
But there's no break because we're leaving tomorrow morning.
Got it?
いよいよ ヒューストンでの
合同基礎訓練が始まるよ！➡
It's finally time to start our joint training in Houston.
つわもの
そこで出会う 各国の強者共は
君らと全くの同期生だ｡
You'll be meeting your talented peers from around the world.
彼女 スゴイよ｡
占いやってたらしいんだけどさ｡
This lady is amazing.
She can tell fortunes.
予知能力もあるんですって！
She can even see the future!
Really?
マジで!?
Does she have super powers?
《それもう 超能力者じゃん》
(ｱﾏﾝﾃｨ)そ そうね…なんか
すごく イイ感じよ｡
S-Sure...
It will go very well...
《ちょっと待て…》
Hold on...
ふおん
《明らかに…不穏な
表情したよな アマンティ》
Amanti looked very disturbed for a moment there.
《こいつがヒビトの兄貴か…｡➡
This is Hibito's older brother?
ふぬ
腑抜けた顔をしてる｡
当然 軍隊経験もなし｡➡
He looks rather dim.
Naturally, he has no military experience.
おく
弟に後れをとっている上に
この締まりのない｢腑抜け顔｣…➡
He's a step behind his little brother, and he looks like a fool.
救いようのない
ノロマだとすぐ分かる》
It's clear that he's a lost cause.
《私が訓練教官に選ばれた以上➡
Since I've been selected as a training instructor,
元軍人として
はんぱ
半端な訓練では終わらせない…｡➡
I must employ my training as a soldier.
軍隊式で いかせてもらう》
I'll give them the military treatment.
１チーム６人制 全５チームに
分かれてもらう｡➡
Divide yourselves into five teams of six.
道具は用意してある｡➡
We have prepared all necessary equipment.
あとは ただ
ひたすら歩いてもらう｡
Once you're ready, begin walking.
それだけだ｡
That will be all.
はあ…あぢぃ…｡
So hot...
《気温４０度》
Forty degrees.
ゆかげん
《これが風呂なら いい湯加減》
The perfect temperature for a bath.
はあ…はあ…はあ…｡
《背負っている荷物
１人平均１２キロ》
Each person carries twelve kilograms of equipment...
《私の心の万歩計では とうに
６千歩は超えた頃だが…》
The pedometer in my heart says that we've taken over six thousand steps.
But the scenery hasn't changed at all.
《全っ然 景色に変化なし》
現在
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)さあ 明日は
サバイバル訓練の最終日｡➡
Well, tomorrow will be the last day of this survival training.
ラストスパートに備えて
そろそろ休もっか｡
We should go to sleep and rest up for the last push.
(北村)そうだね｡
(ｱﾏﾝﾃｨ)そうしましょう｡
You're right.
Let's do that.
炎の番は俺がする｡
みんなは先に寝てくれ｡
I'll watch the fire.
The rest of you can hit the sack.
わぁ～チュロス！
おお～ロケット！
The churro!
The rocket!
あ～いえいえ 何でも…｡
ヘヘヘ ホントホント…｡
Oh, never mind.
It was nothing...
ハハハ…ヘ…ヘ…ヘックシュン！
As you place your hopes on the distant moon
And leave on your journey
You smile in spite of your loneliness
Because you believe in yourself
It doesn't matter if your wings don't match
Spread them out
As you
begin your long journey (try now) (try now)
I'm sure you can make it
Please don't hesitate
to move straight forward
You took
all your pain and sorrow (no more) (no more)
And turned it into your strength
So I'm sure even your destiny to fight many a battle
Is on your side
#55 Distant Goal
Next time, on
Space Brothers
It's the last day of survival training.
＜サバイバル訓練 最終日｡
私は やってしまった＞
But I've done it now.
Nanba, you have a terrible fever!
＜南波さん すごい熱！＞
We have five minutes to decide if our team withdraws.
(ｱﾏﾝﾃｨ)＜全員リタイアするか
５分で決めろって＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Distant Goal"
＜情けねえな いつも 俺は＞
I always screw up.